你来这里是要杀我的
You came here to kill me.
来自第80区：嫌犯尼德曼应该被认为是极其危险的
From precinct 80: the suspect Niedermann should be regarded as extremely dangerous.
要格外小心
Exercise extreme caution.
所有巡逻队都确认81-20 完毕
All patrols acknowledge. 81-20, over.
81-20 你收到了吗 完毕
81-20, are you receiving? Over.
八一二零你收到了吗 完毕
Eight-one-two-zero. Are you receiving? Over.
她的名字是丽斯贝丝·萨兰德
Her name is Lisbeth Salander.
她今年27岁
She is 27 years old.
在本期的千禧年报中 我们揭示了
In this edition of Millennium we reveal...
瑞典政府官员如何密谋反对她
...how Swedish government officials have conspired against her...
来掩盖一个犯罪疯狂的杀人犯：
...to cover up a criminally insane murderer:
亚历山大·萨拉琴科 一名来自苏联的叛徒GRU特工
Alexander Zalachenko, a turncoat GRU agent from the Soviet Union.
在瑞典 他犯下了严重罪行：
In Sweden he has committed serious crimes:
武器走私 毒品交易 洗钱 袭击
arms smuggling, drug dealing, money laundering, assault.
亚历山大·萨拉琴科是利斯贝思·萨兰德的父亲
Alexander Zalachenko is Lisbeth Salander's father.
这一期的《千禧年》讲述了她对故事的看法
This edition of Millennium tells her side of the story.
你好
Hello.
你能睁开眼睛吗
Can you open your eyes?
我叫安德斯·乔纳森 我是你的医生
My name is Anders Jonasson. l am your doctor.
您现在在哥德堡的Sahlgrenska医院
You are at the Sahlgrenska hospital in Göteborg.
你能数到十吗
Can you count to ten?
一 二 三
One, two, three...
那好吧
That's okay.
我的文章大约有40到50页长
My article is about 40 to 50 pages long.
它将包含比约克调查的摘录
It will contain extracts from Björck's investigation...
让它更强大 更有说服力
...to make it stronger, more convincing.
我们有什么图像 - 没有太多
What images have we got? - Not much.
我们可以得到贡纳·比约克、泰勒博里安和萨拉琴科的照片
We can get pictures of Gunnar Björck, Teleborian and Zalachenko.
和一些圣斯蒂芬医院 - 是的 还有利斯贝思
And some of St. Stephen's Hospital. - Yes, and of Lisbeth.
这听起来至少有75页 - 可能会更多会很好的
It sounds like at least 75 pages. - It may be more. It will be good.
我们能找到更多的名字吗 - 不 我们必须专注于我们所拥有的
Can we find more names? - No, we must focus on what we have.
让我们希望这份出版物能带来其他名字
Let's hope that the publication brings out other names.
那只是时间问题 然后
That will be only a matter of time, and then...
我们现在开始工作吧
Let's get to work now.
突发新闻：今天早上戈塞贝加附近的谋杀案发生后 警方已经调动了额外的力量
Breaking news: police have mobilised extra forces after the murder near Gosseberga this morning.
目前正在对嫌疑人进行大规模追捕
A massive manhunt is being undertaken for the suspect.
警方已经确认了他的身份
Police have identified him...
扮演罗纳德·尼德曼 一个35岁的德国人
...as Ronald Niedermann, a 35 year old German.
根据警方的说法 他持有武器 非常危险
According to police he is armed and very dangerous.
我在找弗雷德里克·克林顿 - 我该说您是哪位
I am looking for Fredrik Clinton. - Who shall I say is calling?
埃弗特·古尔伯格 我的老同事
Evert Gullberg, an old colleague.
爸爸在睡觉 请进来吧
Dad is sleeping, but come inside please.
无论后果如何 萨拉琴科都会做对自己最好的事情
Zalachenko will do what is best for himself, whatever the consequences.
这也关系到我的声誉
lt is also about my reputation.
我们不能冒险让他开口
We cannot risk him talking.
我们要不惜一切代价让他闭嘴
We need to silence him at any cost.
我们都同意就像我们平时一样
We agree. Like we usually do.
你可以看到 我现在的状态
You can see what condition l am in.
弗雷德里克 我们需要你最后一次
Fredrik, we need you. One last time.
我不行
I can't.
每隔一天 我就会待五个小时
Every other day l stay five hours...
在医院做血液透析
...at the hospital for haemodialysis.
我很快就要死了
I will die soon!
我得不到新的肾脏
I cannot get a new kidney.
就是这样 我的朋友
That's how it is, my friend.
谢谢你 亲爱的 - 它们是新鲜出炉的
Thank you, my dear. - They are freshly baked.
我不知道你有个女儿
l did not know you had a daughter.
不
No...
我们对彼此的私生活知之甚少
We don't know much about each other's private lives.
尽管我们一起工作过
Although we have worked together...
哦 是的 超过35年了
...oh yes, more than 35 years.
丽斯贝丝·萨兰德呢
What about Lisbeth Salander?
起诉程序已经开始我们要拿她怎么办
The prosecution process has already started. What will we do with her?
你好 丽斯贝丝
Hello Lisbeth.
怎么样
How's it going?
你还记得我吗 安德斯·乔纳森是我的名字
Do you remember me? Anders Jonasson is my name.
如果你累了 我会理解的
l understand if you're tired.
你头部中弹
You were shot in the head.
我们设法把子弹取出来了
We managed to remove the bullet.
据我们所知 它没有损坏任何重要区域
lt has not damaged any vital areas, as far as we know.
你的右肩和左髋部也有枪伤
You also had gunshot wounds in your right shoulder and left hip.
但它会很好地愈合的
But it will heal nicely.
那脑部损伤呢
What about brain damage?
脑损伤很复杂 有时很难发现别担心
Brain injuries are complex and sometimes difficult to detect. Don't worry.
警察想和你谈谈
The police want to talk with you.
但我因为你的情况拒绝了你
But I said no because of your condition
他们一定会回来的 但现在 我不会让他们见你
They're bound to return, but right now l will not let them see you.
萨拉琴科活了下来吗
Did Zalachenko survive?
他已经痊愈 情况稳定
He has been patched up and is stable.
但他的伤势相当严重
But he is rather seriously injured.
他妈的
Shit.
我在想你什么时候会出现
l was wondering when you would show up.
我们已经讨论了我们可以如何帮助你
We have discussed how we can help you.
但要制定一项战略 我们必须首先听取您的版本
But to develop a strategy, we must first hear your version.
战略应该是什么样子的
What should the strategy look like?
我们会一起找到出路的
We will find a way out together.
然而 要让你完全摆脱牢狱之灾是很难的
However, it will be hard to keep you out of prison completely.
没有狗屎
No shit?
我们会为您提供律师和其他您需要的一切帮助
We will help you with a lawyer and everything else you need.
但你们必须合作 并给我们一些保证
But you must cooperate and give us some guarantees.
尼德曼尼德曼是替罪羊
Niedermann... Niedermann is the scapegoat.
就是他射杀了莉斯贝丝
lt was he who shot Lisbeth.
对你的指控很严重 很难不考虑
There are serious allegations against you which can be difficult to discount.
那是你的问题
That's your problem...
这完全是你的问题
...it's entirely your problem.
如果你不解决它
lf you do not solve it...
我将与媒体联系
...l will contact the press.
我有名字 日期 事件 所有的一切
I have names, dates, events... everything.
我可以彻底摧毁你们所有人
I can crush all of you completely.
我是个幸存者 你现在应该知道了
I am a survivor, you ought to know that by now.
萨拉琴科 你不明白 - 是你不明白
Zalachenko, you do not understand... - It is you who doesn't understand!
我们的谈话到此为止
This conversation is over.
还有一件事
Just one more thing.
丽斯贝丝
Lisbeth...
她怎么了 - 必须把她放到一边 明白吗
What is wrong with her? - She has to be put out of the way, understood?
好的很好
Good. Good...
你好对不起 我来晚了
Hello. Sorry l'm late.
我妹妹到了我们待会儿再谈
My sister has arrived. We'll talk later.
家里没人吗 - 没有
ls there no one at home? - No.
然而 米克 她试图用斧头把父亲打死
However, Micke, she tried to beat her father to death with an axe.
这就是谋杀未遂
And that's attempted murder.
或者是自卫
Or self - defence.
但她因企图谋杀萨拉琴科而被捕 对吧
But she has been arrested for the attempted murder of Zalachenko, right?
因此 她需要一名刑事律师
Therefore she will need a criminal lawyer.
你的做法是女权
Your practice is women's rights.
丽斯贝丝和她的母亲受到虐待和虐待
Lisbeth and her mother were exposed to mistreatment and abuse...
被萨拉琴科和当局 它早在戈塞贝加之前就开始了
...by Zalachenko and by the authorities. It started long before Gosseberga.
以下是证实这一点的文件
Here are documents that confirm it.
一份调查副本 由安全局特工冈纳尔·比约克整理
A copy of the investigation, consolidated by an agent of the Security Service: Gunnar Björck.
这证明了把一个12岁的女孩关在圣斯蒂芬大教堂是多么违法
It proves how illegal it was to lock up a twelve - year - old girl at St. Stephen's...
并让她闭嘴
...and to silence her.
这是保密的吗
ls this confidential?
只要告诉他们你是从一位不愿透露来源的记者那里得到的
Just tell them you have it from a journalist who doesn't want to reveal the origin.
你真的想为了莉斯贝丝·萨兰德走到那个极端 不是吗
You really want to go to that extreme for Lisbeth Salander, don't you?
是
Yes.
从斯德哥尔摩开出的SJ X2000 429次列车已抵达6号站台
SJ's X2000 No. 429 from Stockholm has arrived at platform number 6.
我不需要律师
l do not need a lawyer.
你将被指控企图谋杀你父亲
You will be accused of the attempted murder of your father.
米克认为他们会再次试图把你关进精神病院
Micke thinks that they will try to lock you away in a mental hospital again...
所以你需要一个律师
...so you will need a lawyer.
然而 你确实有一个选择
However, you do have a choice.
如果你不想让法庭任命一名公职律师
If you don't want the court to appoint a public lawyer.
你的沉默意味着我该走了吗
Does your silence mean I should go?
你决定吧
You decide.
你有烟吗
Do you have a cigarette?
你们有尼古丁贴片吗 - 有 请稍等
Do you have a nicotine patch? - Yes, one moment please.
我从米克那里拿到了这份副本你知道里面是什么 不是吗
I got this copy from Micke. You know what's in it, don't you?
我们将需要相互交谈很多
We will need to talk with each other a lot.
所以 我希望你对我完全诚实
So, l want you to be completely honest with me.
米克大部分都告诉我了 但有些事他想让你
Micke told me most of it, but on some matters he wants you...
来决定你想说什么
...to decide what you want to tell.
我想你知道他的意思
I assume you know what he means.
这跟电脑和DVD有关
It's something to do with computers and a DVD.
在多年来我们为你做了这么多之后
After everything we've done for you over the years...
你在威胁我们 这是一个很大的风险
...you are threatening us. That's a big risk.
我是一个幸存者 我做了 我认为生存所必需的事情
I am a survivor. l do what l think is necessary to survive.
不 你这么做是因为你是一个没有荣誉的邪恶的人
No, you do it because you are an evil and wicked man without honour.
没有道德
Without morality.
我来到这里 向您转达我们的口信
l came here to give you our message.
这次我们不会帮你了就是这样
We will not help you this time. So there!
我别无选择你还不明白吗
I have no choice. Don't you understand that?
生活告诉我 总是有选择的
Life has taught me that there's always a choice.
白痴
Idiots.
我压死你了 - 你什么都不会做
l crush you. - You will not do anything.
不 躺着别动请!我会看到发生了什么
No, lie still. Please! l'll see what's going on.
滚出去
Get out!
他有枪
He has a gun!
到底怎么回事
What's going on?
快点
Hurry!
等等 我来了抓紧我
Wait, I'm coming. Hold me tightly.
抱着我
Hold me.
抓紧我
Hold me tightly!
他拉了门 但打不开这太超现实了
He pulled the door, but could not open it. lt was so surreal.
一个拿着枪的老人
An old man with a gun.
然后 我听到了自杀的枪声
Then l heard the shot when he killed himself.
你确定他想联系利斯贝思吗
Are you sure that he tried to get hold of Lisbeth?
是的 太可怕了 我从来没有这么害怕过
Yes, it was awful! l have never been so scared.
你想让我下来吗 - 不
Do you want me to come down? - No.
没这个必要 我将和我的朋友维拉·科伦德一起住在卡尔托普
That's not necessary. l will stay with my friend Vera Åkerlund in Kålltorp.
15点在警察总部召开新闻发布会 - 我要走了
Press conference at police headquarters at 15. - l'll have to run.
照顾好你自己 - 是的
Look after yourself. - Yes.
我们待会儿再谈 - 是的再见
We'll talk later. - Yes. Bye.
为什么警察不设立一个更好的警戒呢
Why didn't the police set up a better watch?
太不可思议了你不会想到这样的事情会发生在这里
Absolutely incredible. You wouldn't think such things could happen here.
携带武器进入医院科室并杀害病人 真的令人难以置信
To go armed into a hospital department and kill a patient, is really unbelievable!
好吧 我永远不会 弗雷德里克
Well l never! Fredrik?
到底发生了什么事 请进 请进
What in the world's happened? Come in please, come in.
我们现在正在努力获取有关它的信息
We're trying to get information about it now.
那是几点 找出答案
What time was it? Find out.
搞什么鬼
What the hell?
你知道发生了什么吗 - 萨拉琴科中枪了
Do you know what happened? - Zalachenko has been shot.
似乎是埃弗特·古尔伯格开枪打死了他
lt seems Evert Gullberg shot him.
下面一片混乱目前还没有任何消息得到证实
lt's chaos down there. Nothing has been confirmed.
那么 我会确认的是埃弗特开枪打死了他
Then l will confirm it. lt was Evert who shot him.
就像计划的那样
Just as planned.
你想喝咖啡什么的吗 - 不 现在不想
Would you like coffee or something? - No, not now.
见鬼 你在说什么 什么计划
What the hell are you talking about? What plans?
古尔伯格只剩下几个月的生命了他得了肝癌
Gullberg had only a few months left to live. He had liver cancer.
他选择为我们做最后的努力
He chose to make one last effort for us.
他光荣地牺牲了
He died with honour.
你知道他会杀了萨拉琴科吗 - 当然
Did you know he would kill Zalachenko? - Of course.
他的任务是让萨拉琴科闭嘴
His mission was to silence Zalachenko.
还有萨兰德 就像是计划好的一样
And Salander, like it was planned.
你跟古尔伯格一样神经错乱吗
Are you as fucking deranged as Gullberg?
说话注意点 霍尔伯格这是一个正确的决定
Watch your tongue, Hallberg. It was the right decision.
我们做了必要的事情 - 有必要吗 决定
We did what was necessary. - Necessary? Decision?
你和古尔伯格根本没有权力做任何决定 该死的
You and Gullberg had no mandate to take any decision at all, damn it!
无论发生什么：萨拉琴科的死永远不会与我们有关
Whatever happens: Zalachenko's death will never be related to us.
也不是埃弗特·古尔伯格的
Nor Evert Gullberg's.
我们的任务是做出决定
Our task is to take decisions...
这是其他人都不敢做的
...that no one else dares.
最不用说的是政客就这么简单
Least of all politicians. It's that simple.
还有一件事
One more thing...
我会重操旧业
I will return to action.
我将领导业务活动
l will lead the operational activities...
直到这场危机结束
...until this crisis is over.
开了致命一枪的人后来结束了自己的生命
The man who fired the deadly shot and later took his own life...
已经被确认为78岁的养老金领取者
...has been identified as a 78 year - old pensioner.
他曾当过会计师和税务律师
He has worked as an accountant and tax lawyer.
他叫什么名字 - 我们现在不能透露
What was his name? - We can not disclose that right now.
和莉斯贝丝·萨兰德有联系吗
ls there a connection with Lisbeth Salander?
我们可以坚决否认与利斯贝丝·萨兰德之间可能存在的联系
We can firmly deny a possible link with Lisbeth Salander.
似乎是一个单独的袭击者采取了
It seemed to be a single assailant who has acted...
基于他自己偏执的想象力
...based upon his own paranoid imagination.
他向著名的政治家和媒体发出了令人困惑的信息
He has sent confused messages, to famous politicians and media...
对亚历山大·萨拉琴科发出死亡威胁
...with death threats against Alexander Zalachenko.
安全局已经对其进行了分析 但这名男子可能患有精神疾病
The Security Service has analyzed it, but the man was probably mentally ill.
警方的新闻发布会到此结束
That concludes the police press conference.
我们回到哥德堡Sahlgrenska医院的事件中
We return to the incidents at Sahlgrenska hospital in Göteborg.
不是的
No!
晚餐 - 当然今天的索尔兹伯里牛排
Dinner? - Indeed. Salisbury steak today.
您先请 - 谢谢你
Go ahead. - Thank you.
丽斯贝丝
Lisbeth?
需要帮忙吗 - 不用了 谢谢
Do you need help? - No thanks.
现在就把它吃完
Eat up now.
我有一个建议
l have a suggestion.
我不会开车回家 我已经订了一个房间
l'm not driving home. l have booked a room.
你会在这里过夜吗
Will you stay overnight?
我已经筋疲力尽了 我在编辑轮班时睡不好觉
l'm completely exhausted. l slept poorly on the editorial shift.
那我们就睡吧
Then we just sleep.
这是这辆车第四次出现在那里
It's the fourth time that car has been there.
你确定吗 - 确定
Are you sure? - Yes.
你打算如何解决这个问题 - 我们无法预料到一切
How do you propose to solve this? - We could not anticipate everything.
医院的警卫已经加强了 - 他妈的谢谢你
The guarding of the hospital has been tightened. - Fucking thanks for that!
见鬼 你现在怎么能避免庭审
How the hell are you going to avoid a trial now?
我认为我们做不到
l do not think we can.
只有上了锁的门和精神评估才能把她关起来
Only locked doors and a psychiatric assessment will confine her.
她必须因谋杀萨拉琴科未遂而受到惩罚
She must be punished for the attempted murder of Zalachenko...
并承认接受了精神治疗
...and admitted to secure psychiatric care.
为什么不在圣斯蒂芬这里呢 - 是的
And why not here at St. Stephen's? - Yes.
没有其他原因 只是为了她自己
For no other reason than for her own sake.
检察官叫什么名字
What is the name of the prosecutor?
Ekström不是明星 但雄心勃勃
Ekström. Not a star, but ambitious.
我们能对付他
We can handle him.
比约克的调查复印件呢 - 我们正在收集它们
And what about the copies of Björck's investigation? - We're collecting them now.
你应该很容易做到这一点
You should be easily capable of that.
你担心得太多了
You worry too much.
还有那个为萨拉琴科工作的金发肌肉男
And that blond muscleman who worked for Zalachenko?
他怎么了 - 罗纳德·尼德曼
What happened to him? - Ronald Niedermann.
他正在逃亡
He is on the run.
这只是个时间问题
It's just a matter of time.
他是利斯贝丝·萨兰德同父异母的兄弟
He is Lisbeth Salander's half - brother.
萨拉琴科在汉堡与一名女子有染
Zalachenko had an affair with a woman in Hamburg.
这听起来像是一场该死的希腊悲剧
It sounds like a goddamned Greek tragedy.
萨拉琴科试图在她哥哥的帮助下杀害他的女儿
Zalachenko tried to kill his daughter with the help of her brother.
然后她起死回生
Then she returned from the dead...
在她父亲的头上放了一把斧头
...and put an axe in her father's head.
是的 你可能是这么想的
Yes, you might think of it that way.
你会收到我的来信的
You will hear from me.
再见 维拉再见
See you again, Vera. Bye.
嘿!把包还给我
Hey! Give me back the bag!
把我的包给我
Give me my bag!
见鬼的
What the hell...!
有人骑滑板车抢走了我的包
Someone on a scooter snatched my bag.
什么 那你还好吗 你没事吧
What? How are you then? Are you okay?
我很好但比约克的调查是在袋子里进行的
l am fine. But Björck's investigation was in the bag.
别担心我会复印一份
Don't worry. I'll make a copy.
安妮卡 我会再打给你的
Annika, I'll call you again.
米尔顿安全公司 阿曼斯基
Milton Security, Armanskij.
这位是米凯尔·布隆维斯特 我需要你的帮助
This is Mikael Blomkvist. l need your help.
出什么事了 - 有人闯进了我家
What is the problem? - Someone has broken into my house.
我们可以帮你做到这一点我可以从我的办公室给你打电话吗
We can help you with that. Can I call you from my office?
当然可以 用你的手机打给我 - 好的 再见
Of course, call me from your mobile. - Okay, bye.
对利斯贝思·萨兰德的起诉并不复杂
The indictment against Lisbeth Salander is not complicated.
即使原告萨拉琴科已经死了
Even if the plaintiff Zalachenko is dead.
然而 如果关于萨拉琴科的一切都公之于众 那么这将是一场非常复杂的审判
However, if everything about Zalachenko comes out, then it's going to be a very complicated trial.
它关乎人命 关乎我们与外国势力的关系
lt is about human lives, about our relationship with a foreign power...
和安全局的秘密联系人
...and the secret contacts of the Security Service.
是的 我已经阅读了这篇报道的背景材料
Yes, l've read the report as background material.
对于对利斯贝丝·萨兰德的起诉来说 这份报告几乎没有相关性
For the prosecution of Lisbeth Salander the report has little relevance...
检察官已经没收了它
...and the Director of Public Prosecutions has confiscated it.
然而 它的部分内容是有用的
Nevertheless, parts of it are useful.
尤其是利斯贝丝·萨兰德过去曾试图暗杀她的父亲
Especially where Lisbeth Salander tried to assassinate her father in the past.
我看看你能不能接触到那个部分
I will see if you can have access to that part.
是的 这可能是有益的
Yes, it might be beneficial.
那么 我会保证你拿到的
Then l will ensure that you get it.
你的上级是谁
Who is your superior?
我的命令来自最高层
My orders come from the very top.
这意味着你不能和任何人谈论这件事 除了我
This means that you cannot talk to anyone about this but me.
我会非常谨慎的
I will be very discreet.
安德斯·乔纳森 - 是的
Anders Jonasson? - Yes.
我叫彼得·泰尔伯里安
My name is Peter Teleborian.
我是乌普萨拉圣斯蒂芬精神病院的一名医生
l am a doctor at St. Stephen's psychiatric clinic in Uppsala.
我有话跟你说
l need to talk to you.
是关于你的一个病人 丽斯贝丝·萨兰德
It is about one of your patients, Lisbeth Salander.
我明白了 - 好吧 好吧
I see... - Well... okay.
我从她12岁起就开始和她打交道
I have been dealing with her since she was twelve years old...
我对她的临床情况有很好的了解
...and I have a very good understanding of her clinical picture.
它看起来像什么 - 丽斯贝丝有严重的精神障碍
What does it look like? - Lisbeth is seriously mentally disturbed.
她有明显的妄想症和精神分裂症的特征
She has overt delusions with paranoid and schizophrenic features.
像所有反社会的人一样 她完全缺乏同理心
And like all sociopaths she completely lacks empathy.
简单地说
To put it simply.
我认为她是一个封闭的人 但不是一个偏执的反社会者
I perceive her as a closed person, but not as a paranoid sociopath.
她非常善于操纵 这是疾病图景的一部分
She is extremely manipulative, which is part of the disease picture.
她展示了她认为你想看的东西
She shows what she thinks you want to see.
正如你所理解的 我对她的精神状况感到非常担忧
As you will understand, l feel great concern about her mental condition.
我知道了
Yes, I understand.
我得去见她 在开庭前评估一下她的情况
I'll have to see her to assess her condition before the trial.
那件事我帮不了你
I cannot help you with that.
利斯贝丝由 我负责
l am responsible for Lisbeth.
除了她的律师之外 她身体不够强壮 不能见任何人
She is not strong enough to meet anyone other than her lawyer.
我已受检察官指示与她见面
l have been instructed by the prosecutor to meet with her.
我曾希望避免拘泥于礼节 但现在我想我不得不这样了
I had hoped to avoid being formal, but now I suppose I'll have to be.
作为一名医生 你应该知道我的评估是适用的
As a doctor you should know that it's my assessment that applies...
无论检察官的决定如何
...regardless of prosecutor decisions.
因此 你必须耐心等待 直到 我改变我的评估
Therefore, you will have to be patient and wait until l change my assessment.
好吧
Well...
我曾希望得到一个更专业的回应
I had hoped for a more professional response.
我们能排除政府对此知情的可能性吗
Can we rule out government knowledge of it?
他们一定知道有一名俄罗斯间谍叛逃到瑞典
They must have known that a Russian spy defected to Sweden.
76年萨拉琴科叛逃时 我们有一个保守的政府
We had a conservative government in '76 when Zalachenko defected.
30年来 没有任何东西泄露出去
30 years and nothing has leaked out.
如果许多政客都知道这件事 这件事就不可能保密
lt could not be kept secret, if a lot of politicians were aware of it.
他们中的许多人现在都在写传记
A lot of them write biographies now.
安全局也是如此它迟早会泄露出去的
The same goes for the Security Service. lt would have leaked out sooner or later.
一定有一个小的秘密组织在自己行动
There must be a small secret group acting on their own.
拥有大量的资源和影响力
With substantial resources and influence.
如果30年来没有人泄露这个组织的消息 我们从哪里开始挖掘
lf nobody has leaked about the group in 30 years, where do we start digging?
我们最好的线索是埃弗特·古尔伯格
The best lead we have is Evert Gullberg.
如果我们对他有更多的了解 就有可能有所进展
If we find out more about him, there is a chance of getting somewhere.
然而 这不能花太长时间 否则千禧年将陷入困境
However, it must not take too long or Millennium will be in trouble.
这本杂志必须与审判同时出版
The magazine must be out simultaneously with the trial.
请看着这个
Keep your eye on this, please.
我做得怎么样 - 你明显进步了
How am I doing? - You are clearly improving.
我将确保你得到帮助 开始康复
l will ensure that you get help to get started with rehabilitation.
我不需要帮助 - 你有 不要刮伤疤
I do not need help. - You do. Don't scratch the scab.
此外 你应该吃得更好
Moreover, you should eat better.
你应该对食物做点什么
You should do something about the food.
吃的 - 给我拿个披萨或类似的东西
The food? - Get me a pizza or something like that.
我怀疑预算是否足够买披萨
I doubt the budget is sufficient for pizza.
一位彼得·泰尔博里安医生想见你
A Dr. Peter Teleborian wanted to see you.
他说你们过去有过接触
He said that you'd had contact in the past.
无论如何 他不得不空手而归
Anyway, he had to leave empty - handed.
很好
Good...
显然这是给你的
Apparently this is for you.
你好我们在利斯贝丝·萨兰德被带到医院的那晚见过面
Hello. We met at the hospital the night Lisbeth Salander was brought in.
是的 我确实记得 - 我想和你谈一件事
Yes, I do remember. - l want to talk to you about something.
我不会透露有关利斯贝丝·萨兰德的信息
I will not disclose information about Lisbeth Salander.
不 我想给你一些关于丽斯贝丝的信息重要信息
No, I want to give you information about Lisbeth. Important information.
像这样的阴谋 抱歉 听起来不太可能
A conspiracy like that... sorry, but it sounds very unlikely.
我理解你的看法 但 我向你保证：一切都是真的
I understand that you see it that way, but l assure you: everything is true.
一切都可以记录下来 我会公布整个故事
Everything can be documented and l will publish the whole story.
我为利斯贝思的庭审辩护这就是我在这里的原因
I built Lisbeth's defence for her trial. That's why I am here.
我只想问你一件事 - 什么
l'm only going to ask you about one thing. - What?
丽斯贝丝有秘密
Lisbeth has secrets.
私人的她可能需要它们来为自己辩护
Private ones. She may need them for her defence.
以获取她需要的证据
To access the evidence she will need this.
检察官已经施加了限制 - 这就是 我问你的原因
The prosecutor has imposed restrictions. - That's why l'm asking you.
嗨 你好吗 - 很好
Hi, how are you doing? - Fine.
我可以给你做个简单的检查吗 - 可以
May I give you a brief examination? - Yes.
我们来看看
Let's have a look...
你感觉到疼痛吗 - 没有
Do you feel any pain? - No.
头疼呢 - 还不错
What about headaches? - Not bad.
它们正在逐渐消失 - 那很好
They are disappearing gradually. - That's good.
斯德哥尔摩警方又打来电话
The Stockholm police called again.
汉斯·法斯特是他的名字他称自己是调查的负责人
Hans Faste was his name. He described himself as in charge of the investigation.
他想来这里审问你
He wanted to come here and interrogate you.
你的头能稍微向后仰一点吗
Can you bend your head slightly backwards?
不会太远他们如此执着 我有点恼火
Not too far. I was a little annoyed that they are so persistent.
我不能再用你的身体状况来拒绝他了
l cannot use your medical condition to refuse him much longer.
你进步很快你明白吗
You are improving rapidly. Do you understand?
我告诉他 你还需要几个星期的时间来康复
l told him that you need a couple of weeks more to rehabilitate.
然后你将被转移到斯德哥尔摩的监狱
You will then be moved to jail in Stockholm.
我看到你背上的纹身了它看起来很大
I saw the tattoo on your back. It seems quite large.
你为什么要这么做 - 为什么这么问
Why did you get it done? - Why do you ask?
纯粹的好奇心 - 由于私人原因 我不会讨论
Pure curiosity. - For private reasons I will not discuss.
好吧抱歉的
Okay. Sorry.
那一定很痛 也花了不少时间
lt must have hurt and taken time.
是的 对两个人都是
Yes, to both.
打扰了
Excuse me.
你好 丽斯贝丝有了这个 你可以告诉你所发生的事情的版本
Hello Lisbeth. With this you can tell your version of what happened.
你的自传
Your autobiography.
安妮卡不知道你现在有了PDA 最好还是让它保持原样
Annika doesn't know that you have your PDA now, and it's better to keep it that way.
我应该把DVD给她吗
Should I give her the DVD?
我们还需要更多地了解Teleborian
We also need to know more about Teleborian.
我住在你的公寓里我的手机被监视了 可能还被窃听了
I live in your apartment. Mine is under surveillance and probably bugged.
谋杀嫌疑人利斯贝丝·萨兰德将从哥德堡的萨尔格伦斯卡被转移
Murder suspect Lisbeth Salander will be transferred from Sahlgrenska in Göteborg...
在她的情况允许的情况下尽快送到斯德哥尔摩的克罗诺贝格监狱
...to Kronoberg prison in Stockholm as soon as her condition allows...
根据警方发言人的说法
...according to a police spokesman.
审判定于今年11月初进行
The trial is scheduled for the beginning of November this year.
瘟疫 你在吗
Plague, are you there?
把DVD给安妮卡也没关系不过 我将亲自写下这起强奸事件
It's okay to give the DVD to Annika. However, l will write about the rape myself.
我已经联系了普雷格关于Teleborian的事情
I have contacted Plague about Teleborian.
如果他发现了什么 他会联系你的
He will contact you if he finds something.
我与政府有关联
l have a link to the government.
猜猜1976年10月5日 谁在内阁府拜访了首相
Guess who visited the Prime Minister at the Cabinet Office on October 5, 1976?
没人要吗 埃弗特·古尔伯格和一个叫汉斯·冯·罗廷格的人
No takers? Evert Gullberg and a person named Hans von Rottinger.
在萨拉琴科叛逃三周后 他们就在那里
They were there three weeks after Zalachenko defected.
你怎么知道的 - 我查了留言簿
How did you find out? - I checked the visitor's book.
只有一次访问 那是1976年10月5日
There was only one visit, on October 5, 1976.
干得好 克里斯特
Well done, Christer.
然而 必须证明他们在那里是为了提供关于萨拉琴科的信息
Nevertheless, it must be proved that they were there to provide information on Zalachenko.
有什么记录吗 - 没有 只有名字和日期
Were there any notes? - No, just names and dates.
我们要怎么做 - 我们必须检查国务卿
How do we proceed? - We must check the Secretaries of State.
在那里工作的两个人可能知道些什么 - 我们有名字吗
Two people who worked there might know something. - Do we have any names?
其中一人去世 另一人是一名退休大使
One is dead and the other one is a retired ambassador.
他的名字叫Bengt Janeryd 住在格里斯勒姆郊外
His name is Bengt Janeryd and he lives outside Grisslehamn.
我们应该和他聊聊 - 很好 我会处理好的
We should have a chat with him. - Good. I'll take care of that.
我比你更了解这个案子 所以我对他更危险
I know the case better than you do, so I am more dangerous to him.
我就是这么说的 - 是的 我听到你说的了
lt's just what I say. - Yes, I heard what you said...
地址是什么
Address?
好吧
Okay.
而你
And you...
干得好
...well done!
你一定知道古尔伯格枪杀了萨拉琴科 对吧
You must know that Gullberg has shot Zalachenko, right?
你在报纸上看到了吗 - 是的
Did you read it in the newspapers? - Yes.
你为什么不报警 - 我一直在等他们的电话
Why didn't you call the cops? - I waited for them to call.
这听起来有点方便 - 我对女儿一无所知
That sounds a little convenient. - l knew nothing about his daughter.
她所遭受的痛苦是可怕的
What she suffered is terrible.
然而 首相并不知道这一点
However, the prime minister was not aware of it.
我也不是
Neither was l.
你最好说服我和千禧年读者相信这一点
You'd better convince me and the Millennium readers about that.
我禁止你在这种情况下使用我的名字
I forbid you to use my name in this context.
我与此无关
l didn't have anything to do with it.
我在这里读到的东西对我来说是新的
What I read here is new to me.
你只读了我们将出版的部分材料我们有更多的信息
You have read only some of the material we will publish. We have a lot more.
一切都是可以证明的
Everything can be proved.
我不会把你挂在外面 但你有责任 有责任
l will not hang you out, but you have a responsibility and a liability.
所以要么你现在就告诉我 要么你一直躲在你的保密背后
So either you tell me now, or you keep hiding behind your confidentiality.
这就是我所说的勒索 - 随便你怎么叫
That's what I call blackmail. - Call it whatever you want.
如果你开口 我答应你不提你的名字
lf you talk, l promise you not to mention your name.
首相是否与埃弗特·古尔伯格和汉斯·冯·罗廷格有过接触
Did the prime minister have contact with Evert Gullberg and Hans von Rottinger?
你也联系他们了吗 - 联系了
Did you also contact them? - Yes.
还有一个人叫克林顿 和美国总统一样
There was one more, named Clinton, like the American president.
克林顿 - 是的
Clinton? - Yes.
你们多久见面一次
How often did you meet?
在我担任国务卿期间 有十几次
A dozen times during my time as a Secretary of State.
我什么都不知道只是萨拉琴科合作了
I didn't know anything. Only that Zalachenko collaborated...
他提供的信息是无价的
...and that the information he gave was invaluable.
那么是谁接手了这条线路
Who took over the connection then?
我也不知道
I do not know.
你没有向任何人做简报吗 - 没有
You did not brief anyone? - No.
你没有写任何报告吗
And you didn't write any report?
不 当然 一切都是最高机密
No, everything was top secret, of course.
我甚至在开会时都不做笔记
I didn't even take notes during meetings.
所以 后来的政府都不知道
So, no subsequent government had any idea...
瑞典有一个苏联叛逃者
...that there was a Soviet defector in Sweden?
这可能听起来很奇怪 但事实就是这样
It might sound strange, but that's how it was.
怎么了 普雷格 - 我们有麻烦了
What's up Plague? - We have a problem.
我检查了Teleborian的硬盘和电子邮件 但什么也没有找到
I have checked Teleborian's hard disk and e - mail but found nothing.
什么都没有 - 没有关于你或审判的事
Nothing? - Nothing about you or the trial.
唯一有趣的可能是两封简短的电子邮件
The only thing that might be interesting are two short e - mails...
由乔纳斯通过Hotmai我发送
...sent by Jonas through Hotmail.
PSU 1下周准备好了 从今年9月20日开始
"PSU 1 ready next week". It is from September 20 this year.
第二个同样简短： PSU 2明天就准备好了
The second is equally brief: "PSU 2 ready tomorrow".
PSU 精神病方面的意见
PSU? Psychiatric opinion?
是的 有可能是这样
Yes, it could be.
没有文件吗 - 没有
No files? - No.
他没有从他的工作电脑上发送任何东西
He did not send anything from his work computer.
他可能有一台带移动宽带的笔记本电脑
He probably has a laptop with mobile broadband.
它可能很难访问 - 但不是不可能
It may be difficult to access. - But not impossible?
在正确的时间 一切皆有可能
At the right time, anything is possible.
我会盯着他的邮箱的 - 去做吧但别再给我打电话了
I will keep an eye on his mailbox. - Do it. But don't call me again.
给我发短信或电子邮件 - 好的 再见
Send me an SMS or e - mail. - Okay, bye.
该死的
Damn it!
你好 米凯尔·布隆维斯特 我是莫妮卡·菲格罗拉 宪法保护股
Hello, Mikael Blomkvist. l am Monica Figuerola, Constitutional Protection Unit.
什么事 - 我想请你谈谈
Yes? - I would like to invite you for a talk.
这是一次友好的邀请你不会冒任何风险
It is a friendly invitation. You don't risk anything.
我能先拿到我的邮件吗 - 当然
Can I get my mail first? - Of course.
还有一条干净的内裤 - 当然
And a pair of clean underpants? - Absolutely.
托尔斯滕·埃德克林斯 宪法保护组
Torsten Edklinth, Constitutional Protection Unit.
布隆维斯特 - 请坐
Blomkvist. - Please, take a seat.
你可能明白我们为什么想见你了
You probably understand why we want to meet you.
所以让我们开门见山吧
So let's get to the point.
我们已经得到确认 有一个秘密组织 一个阴谋
We have received confirmation that there exists a secret group, a conspiracy...
在国家行政管理的一个异常敏感的领域
...in an exceptionally sensitive area of state administration.
我昨天晚上与总理的会晤导致了一项全面调查
My meeting with the Prime Minister yesterday evening has resulted in a full investigation.
这意味着
Which means...?
一项全面的调查
A complete investigation.
结果将交给总检察长 由他决定是否应当提起诉讼
The result will go to the General Prosecutor, who will decide whether prosecution should be instituted.
然而 我们需要时间来确定哪些人参与其中
However, we need time to identify those who are involved.
我理解这一点我在其中有什么角色
l understand that. Where do I have a part in it?
我们想知道你打算什么时候出版
We want to know when you plan to publish.
如果在调查完成之前进行 可能会危及整个行动
lf it takes place before the investigation is completed, it could jeopardize the whole operation.
你认为 我什么时候能出版
When do you think that l can publish?
当然 我们还不能确定这一点
Of course we cannot determine that yet.
这完全取决于你 但我请你合作
lt is entirely up to you, but I ask you to cooperate.
让我告诉你这个
Let me tell you this...
国家、政府、特勤局：他们都让我很生气
The state, the government, the Secret Service: they all piss me off...
还有其他所有把一个12岁女孩关起来的混蛋
...and all the other fucking assholes who locked up a twelve - year - old girl...
毫无理由地在精神病院 并使她在法律上无行为能力
...in a mental hospital, for no reason at all, and kept her legally incompetent.
我本人对利斯贝丝·萨兰德的遭遇感到非常难过
l myself am very upset about what happened to Lisbeth Salander.
但责任人将受到惩罚
But those who are responsible will be punished.
但在此之前 我们必须确定谁参与其中
But before that, we must identify who is involved.
这也正是 我想要的
That's exactly what l want as well.
但 我也希望利斯贝思·萨兰德被无罪释放 并被宣布为合法行为能力
But l also want to get Lisbeth Salander acquitted and be declared legally competent.
当然 我们不会干预 也不会有政府的干预 你会明白的
Of course there will be no intervention by us nor by the government, as you will understand.
如果我能完全接触到你的调查结果
Provided that I will get full access to the results of your investigation...
你可以告诉我要出版什么 什么时候出版
...you can tell me what to publish and when.
以信息换取信息
lnformation in exchange for information.
这个问题很容易解决
This can be solved quite easily.
我们决定为调查招募哪些同事
We decide which co - workers we recruit for the investigation.
我们可以聘请Mikael Blomkvist作为外部顾问
We can recruit Mikael Blomkvist as an external consultant.
埃弗特·古尔伯格你还有其他名字吗
Evert Gullberg. Do you have any other names?
汉斯·冯·罗廷格弗雷德里克·克林顿一个人死了 另一个已经退休了
Hans von Rottinger, Frederick Clinton. One is dead, the other has retired.
两人都在70年代和80年代活跃在该组织中 - 该组织
Both were active in the group during the '70 and '80s. - Group?
我们能给它一个暂定的标题吗 也许我们应该叫它 部门
Can we give it a working title? Maybe we should call it "the Section".
分局 好吧
The Section? Okay.
你是怎么发现他们的
How did you find out about them?
我有可靠的消息来源
l have a reliable source.
它应该想出暂定的标题吗 - 当然 我同意这一点
Should it come up with the working title? - Absolutely, l agree with that.
我被绑在床上彼得·泰尔博里安站在床边
I was strapped onto the bed. Peter Teleborian stood next to the bed.
他身上有须后水的味道我讨厌他的气味
He smelled of aftershave. I hated his smell.
我听到他呼吸的变化 看到他的嘴巴在动
l heard his breathing change and saw his mouth move.
但 我听不懂他在说什么
But l didn't understand what he said.
我讨厌他的嘴
I hated his mouth.
那是 我 13岁的那个晚上
It was the night l became 13 years old.
尼德曼是你的兄弟
Niedermann is your brother.
快点 巴斯特 搜查
Come on Buster, search!
是的 搜索 - 80 - 1651 请回答
Yes, search. - 80 - 1651 , come in.
请进 1651
Come in, 1651 .
我们搜查了较低的楼层它是空的
We have searched the lower floor. It's empty.
有人闯入了隔壁的房子 但警察在场
Someone has broken into the house next - door, but the police are present.
你需要什么帮助你入睡的东西吗
Do you need something to help you sleep?
丽斯贝丝几次试图告诉社会服务机构
Lisbeth tried several times to tell the social services...
关于Zalachenko虐待她的母亲
...about Zalachenko's abuse of her mother...
但没有人把这个十岁女孩的指控当回事
...but nobody took the ten year old girl's accusations seriously.
为了救她的母亲 莉斯贝丝最终试图杀死她的父亲
To save her mother Lisbeth eventually tried to kill her father...
把一个装有汽油的牛奶盒扔到他脸上
...by throwing a milk carton with petrol onto his face...
然后是一根燃烧的火柴
...and then a burning match.
然后 社会做出了反应
Then society reacted.
但不是通过惩罚亚历山大·萨拉琴科
But not by punishing Alexander Zalachenko.
相反 利斯贝思受到了惩罚
Instead, Lisbeth was punished.
12岁的她被关在乌普萨拉的圣斯蒂芬精神病院
Twelve years old, she was locked up at St. Stephen's psychiatric hospital in Uppsala.
当她出来时 她在法律上被宣布为无行为能力 并被置于监护之下
When she came out, she was declared legally incompetent and placed under guardianship.
是我
lt's me.
Teleborian将于16：00在中心与Jonas会面
Teleborian will meet with Jonas at 1600 in the centre.
现在几点了 - 差不多三点半了
What time is it now? - Nearly half past three.
该死的
Damn it!
你好 我得验血 - 我只需要上个厕所
Hello. l have to take some blood tests. - l just need to go to the toilet.
是的 克里斯特 - 我在楼梯中央
Yes, Christer. - l'm in the middle of the staircase.
是的 我现在看到你了 我就在下面
Yes, I see you now. l'm just below.
我在大厅中央看到了Teleborian克里斯特 说吧 我将留在这里
l see Teleborian in the centre of the hall. Christer, go ahead. l will stay here.
好吧
Okay.
你应该很快就能见到他黑色夹克
You should see him soon. Black jacket.
我现在就去看他他站在那里等着
l see him now. He's standing and waiting.
盯着他 但别太近了 - 不 我只是在看着他
Keep an eye on him, but not too close. - No, I'm just watching him.
有人来了一定是乔纳斯
Someone is coming. It must be Jonas.
灰色夹克 中年 我不认得他
Gray jacket, middle - aged. l do not recognize him.
现在他们要离开了我应该跟着去吗 - 是的 跟着他们
Now they are leaving. Should I tag along? - Yes, follow them!
他们要去瓦萨加坦 - 继续跟踪他们
They're going out to Vasagatan. - Keep following them.
我是迈克泰勒波里安要见一个为部门工作的人
Mikael here. Teleborian is meeting someone who works for the Section.
好的 在哪里 - 在瓦萨加坦你来吗
Okay, where? - At Vasagatan. Are you coming?
好吧是的 我要来
Okay. Yes, l'm coming.
嗨 - 你好
Hi. - Hello.
他们就在那里
They are there.
我是迈克 - 他们现在要走了
Mikael here. - They are leaving now.
沿着Teleborian行驶我们会跟着另一个人走
Follow Teleborian. We will follow the other one.
我是莫妮卡 我需要一辆车的资料
Monica here. l need information on a car.
猜猜四小时前谁进了同一扇门
Guess who went through the same door four hours ago.
弗雷德里克·克林顿
Fredrik Clinton.
泰尔波里安的声明 - 是草稿
Teleborian's statement? - lt's a draft.
它需要编辑 但看起来很好
lt needs to be edited, but it looks good.
Teleborian是否从与部门的Jonas Sandberg的会议中
Did Teleborian go from a meeting with Jonas Sandberg of the Section...
去警察局开会
...to a meeting at the police station?
和谁 - 我们会查出来的
With whom? - We'll find out.
乔纳斯·桑德伯格于1998年加入安全部门因为反间谍活动
Jonas Sandberg joined the security department in 1998. For counter - espionage.
2001年 他被转移到国外的一个秘密地点
In 2001 he was transferred to a secret location abroad.
他应该在马德里的大使馆工作 但他们从来没有听说过他
He should be working at the embassy in Madrid, but they have never heard of him.
这些是该科的财产
These are the Section's properties.
一栋公寓 六层 23套公寓
A block of apartments, six floors, 23 flats.
我已经检查了所有的租户 但没有发现任何异常
I have checked all tenants but nothing unusual came out.
此外 还有顶层公寓11个房间和一个厨房
Additionally there is the top flat. 1 1 rooms and a kitchen.
一家名为Bellona的公司拥有它房主住在国外
A company named Bellona owns it. The owners live abroad.
我们能在上面装个摄像机吗 - 我们有许可吗
Can we get a camera up there? - Do we have permission for that?
如果你设法弄到一壶茶 我会得到许可的
I will get permission for that, if you manage to get a pot of tea.
不要紧 我会在家里做一个
Never mind, I'll make one at home.
你好 - 嗨
Hello. - Hi.
我打扰你了吗 - 是的
Am l interrupting? - Yes.
我还会来的 - 我已接近尾声
I'll be back. - l have nearly finished it.
我只是想提醒你明天警察就要来了
I just wanted to warn you that the police are coming tomorrow.
好吧
Okay.
我可以推迟几天 但是
I could delay a couple of days, but...
我的同事们会想知道 - 所以让它过去吧
...my colleagues would wonder. - So let it go.
你确定吗 - 确定
Are you sure? - Yes.
你看起来并不特别担心 - 没有
You do not seem particularly worried. - No.
我给你准备了一份礼物
I have a present for you.
为什么
Why?
很久以来 你一直是我最有趣的病人之一
You have been one of my most entertaining patients in a long time.
以防你在监狱里感到无聊反对DNA研究的最新呼声
ln case you should get bored in jail... The latest clamour against DNA research.
你的手机 - 在巧克力盒子里
Your mobile phone... - It's in the chocolate box.
Teleborian将撰写一份专家意见
Teleborian will write an expert opinion.
他会得出结论 你需要安全的精神治疗
He will conclude that you need secure psychiatric care.
检察官要求提供这份报告
The prosecutor has requested the report.
因此 我们将不得不聘请我们自己的专家 他会提出自己的观点
So, we'll have to hire our own expert who will come with his own opinion.
莉斯贝丝 这是为你好
Lisbeth, it's for your own good.
我不会和任何心理医生谈的 我已经说过了
I will not talk to any shrink. l have already said that.
我希望它们能合身
l hope they will fit.
唯一会因此而输的人 就是你
The only one who will lose by it, is you.
丽斯贝丝
Lisbeth...
为莉斯贝丝·萨兰德让路
Stand back for Lisbeth Salander.
你好吗 萨兰德 - 丽斯贝丝
How are you, Salander? - Lisbeth...
你对此有何评论
Do you have any comments?
今天 谋杀案嫌疑人莉斯贝丝·萨兰德已在警方的护送下被转移
Today murder suspect Lisbeth Salander has been transferred under police escort...
从哥德堡的Sahlgrenska到斯德哥尔摩的Kronoberg监狱
...from Sahlgrenska in Göteborg to Kronoberg prison in Stockholm.
根据检察官理查德·埃克斯特伦的说法 审判
According to prosecutor Richard Ekström the trial...
定于11月6日
...has been scheduled for November 6.
丽斯贝丝·萨兰德被捕了
Lisbeth Salander was arrested...
涉嫌企图谋杀她的父亲亚历山大·萨拉琴科
...on suspicion of attempted murder of her father, Alexander Zalachenko...
后来在Sahlgrenska医院被残忍地杀害
...who was brutally murdered at Sahlgrenska Hospital subsequently.
与审判相关的安全措施将会加强
There will be increased security in connection with the trial...
在警方调查期间受到威胁后
...following threats during the police investigation.
桑尼 你什么时候出来的 - 今天早上
Sonny? When the hell did you get out? - This morning.
玛格也来了吗 - 不 他得多待一会儿
Magge too? - No, he'll have to stay a little longer.
很高兴再见到你
Good to see you again.
你被捕的那天警察突袭了我们
The police raided us the day you were arrested.
他们什么也没找到后来那个金发混蛋来了 想找个藏身之处
They found nothing. Later on that blond bastard dropped in and wanted a hideaway...
你知道的：你和Magge的朋友
...you know: your and Magge's buddy.
他不是我的朋友 该死的 整个瑞典都在通缉他
He is not my buddy, damn it! He is wanted throughout Sweden.
这就是为什么他需要一个藏身之处 我派他去维克多那里了
So that's why he needed a hideout. l have sent him to Viktor's place.
他妈的
Fuck...
桑尼
Sonny!
见鬼的
What the hell...
珍妮詹妮
Jenny... Jenny!
詹妮
Jenny!
詹妮?是我 桑尼
Jenny? lt's me, Sonny.
是谁打来的
Who was it?
尼德
Nied...
尼德曼
Niedermann.
维克多 维克多
Viktor, Viktor...
尼德曼他会为此而死的
Niedermann... He will fucking die for this.
他会为此而死的
He will fucking die for this!
丽斯贝丝·萨兰德的自传
"Lisbeth Salander's autobiography"...
有人能证明上面写的是什么吗 - 不可能他们没有任何证据
Can anyone prove what's written there? - Impossible. They don't have any proof.
布隆维斯特不是傻瓜埃里卡·伯杰也不是
Blomkvist is no fool. Nor is Erika Berger.
我们必须更彻底地解决这个问题 以便将它们捆绑在一起
We must address it more thoroughly to tie them up.
按绿色按钮
Press the green button.
我们的时间不多了我们必须加大压力
We do not have much time. We must increase the pressure.
今天轮到谁了 - 是马林的 对吗
Who's turn is it today? - lt's Malin's, right?
嗨怎么样
Hi. How's it going?
你要寿司吗 - 不要鱼我要日式鸡肉
You want sushi? - No fish. Chicken teriyaki for me.
你要去吃午饭吗 米克 - 不 我没有时间
Are you going to have lunch, Micke? - No, I don't have time.
好吧埃里卡 八块
Okay. Erika, eight pieces?
我可以用你的电池换电池吗 我的是平的
Can I replace the battery with yours? Mine is flat.
米克看一看
Micke... have a look.
是个匿名者 我认为这封信和上次寄出的是同一个人
It's someone anonymous. l think it's from the same sender as last time.
你有很多吗 - 我上个星期买了一个
Have you got many? - I got one last week.
你为什么什么都不说 - 我没当回事
Why didn't you say anything? - I didn't take it seriously.
这是我们之间的秘密今天晚些时候我们再多谈一谈
We keep it between us. Let's talk more about it later today.
那 我可以拿去吗 - 拿去吧
May l take it then? - Take it.
你想吃八块吗 - 我今天不是很饿
Would you like to have eight pieces? - I'm not so hungry today.
我会跳过一顿饭
l will skip a meal.
是时候去听证了
Time to go to the hearing.
好吧 我们终于见面了
Well, so we finally meet.
埃克斯特伦 检察官
Ekström, prosecutor.
我们认为这场最初的会面更像是一次对话 而不是审问
We see this initial meeting more like a conversation than an interrogation.
一种在复杂的故事中带来一些秩序的方法
A way to bring some order in the complicated story.
我假设你对此没有任何反对意见
l'm assuming that you don't have anything against it.
对你的指控是很严重的
The charges against you are serious.
然而 作为一名检察官 我必须考虑所有减轻处罚的情况
However, as a prosecutor I have to take into account all mitigating circumstances.
为了你自己 你要意识到这一点 这一点很重要
lt is important that you are aware of that, for your own sake.
这是一个简单的问题回答是或不是
This is a simple question. Answer yes or no.
当你去戈塞贝加见你爸爸的时候
When you went to Gosseberga to meet your daddy...
你当时就已经有杀他的计划了吗
...did you already have plans then to kill him?
然后 我会再次要求辩方鼓励她的当事人做出回应
Then l will ask the defence again to encourage her client respond.
然后我重复一遍 我的当事人决定她是否想要回答
Then I repeat that my client decides whether she wants to answer.
我必须要求辩方与Salander小姐进行一次严肃的谈话
I must ask the defence to have a serious conversation with Miss Salander.
我这样说是为了被告自己
I say this for the defendent's own sake.
好吧
Well...
让 我惊讶的是 她竟然这么娇小娇小 像个小女孩
l was surprised that she was so small and delicate, like a little girl.
审判将于13日开始杂志到时候一定要准备好
The trial begins on the 13th. The magazine has to be ready then.
我们需要在前一周去报刊
We need to go to press the week before.
我们怎样才能做到这一点 - 我们必须互相帮助
How will we be able to do that? - We must help each other.
你和马林写一些关于Telborian的背景和一些关于圣斯蒂芬的事情
You and Malin write about Teleborian's background and a bit about St. Stephen's.
大约30页可以吗
Approximately 30 pages. Is that okay?
好的 那很好 - 很好
Yes, that's fine. - Good.
好吧
Well...
然后还有另一件事
Then there is another thing.
我收到了两封匿名电子邮件
I have received two anonymous e - mails...
在过去的一周里 你应该知道这一点
...during the past week, which you should know about.
威胁
Threats?
他妈的!是哪个该死的笨蛋送来的
Shit! Which damned fool has sent them?
你通知警察了吗 - 我不想警察在这里
Did you notify the police about it? - l don't want the police here.
这对埃里卡来说是一个严重的威胁
It is a serious threat towards Erika.
我们非常认真地对待它但 我不想让警察在办公室里
We take it very seriously. But l don't want to have the cops here at the office.
所以 你就想置之不理 - 我不是这个意思
So, you just want to ignore it? - That's not what I say.
我会用我的方式解决它 - 怎么做
I will solve it my way. - How?
警察不会在意这件事的他们他妈的才不管呢
The police will not care about it. They don't give a shit!
求求你 住手 天哪
Please, stop! My God!
我没有再拿到任何东西 也没有造成任何伤害所以让我们忘掉它吧
l didn't get any more of them, and no harm has been done. So let's forget about it.
下一项 - 30页
Next item. - 30 pages.
丽斯贝丝·萨兰德呢 - 在这种情况下 她很好
What about Lisbeth Salander? - She's doing fine, under the circumstances.
你对这些指控有何看法 - 无可奉告
What do you say about the accusations? - No comment.
你必须为她辩护 而且肯定有话要说
You've got to defend her and surely must have something to say.
你好 我的甜心你要在那里吃饭 对不起 我来晚了
Hello my sweethearts. You're eating there? Sorry l'm late.
太好了 你已经吃过了
Good that you've eaten already.
我 你一定会喜欢的这是利斯贝思的自传
l'm sure you will enjoy this. It's Lisbeth's autobiography.
什么 她什么时候写的
What? When did she write it?
那不重要
That doesn't matter.
比约曼 那是丽斯贝丝的监护人吗
"Bjurman"? Is that Lisbeth's guardian?
这是什么 - 是一部电影
What is this? - It's a movie.
你自己去看看吧
Have a look at it yourself.
利斯贝思在试验期间批准了它的使用 如果它有用的话
Lisbeth approved it's use during the trial, if it comes in handy.
你想来点吗
You want some?
丽斯贝丝·萨兰德现在健康吗 - 是的 她现在可以被审问了
Is Lisbeth Salander healthy now? - Yes, she can be interrogated now.
她的身体很好 - 但也许不是精神上的
Physically she is fine. - But maybe not mentally?
据了解 莉斯贝丝·萨兰德已经在精神病院接受了几年的治疗
lt is known that Lisbeth Salander has been treated in mental hospitals for several years.
你觉得莉斯贝丝·萨兰德还有精神病吗
You think that Lisbeth Salander is still mentally ill?
我无法诊断自己的病情
l'm not able to diagnose her case.
我要求进行精神调查以找到答案
l have asked for a psychiatric investigation to find the answer.
谁将成为医生 - 彼得·泰尔博里安
Who will be the doctor? - Peter Teleborian.
他是圣斯蒂芬医院的首席精神病学家
He is chief psychiatrist at St. Stephen's hospital.
彼得·泰尔博里安真叫人吃惊
Peter Teleborian... what a surprise.
克里斯特
Christer?
是同一个人寄来的吗 - 是的
ls it from the same sender? - Yes.
现在情况变得更糟了对你们所有人来说
"lt's getting worse now. For all of you".
这是关于我们的吗
Is that about us?
米克已经试着追踪发信人了吗 - 他打电话给别人了
Has Micke already tried to trace the sender? - He called somebody.
这并没有起到多大作用我们必须打电话报告这件事
That didn't help much. We must call and report it.
我们不能坐等事情发生 - 我想先和米凯尔谈谈
We cannot just wait for something to happen. - I want to talk to Mikael first.
我现在就给他打电话 - 没有我是负责任的出版商
I will call him right now. - No. I am the responsible publisher.
而且 我就是收到这些电子邮件的人我不会背着麦克尔行事的
Moreover, l am the one who received those e - mails. I will not act behind Mikael's back.
我们必须团结一致团结一心尤其是现在
We must stick together. And be united. Especially now.
我会打电话给迈克尔的
I'll call Mikael.
米克尔·布隆维斯特 我现在无法回复 请留言
Mikael Blomkvist. l cannot reply now, but please leave a message.
米克 你该死的在哪里 我又收到了一封电子邮件
Micke, where the hell are you? I've received another e - mail.
现在这不只是我的事了感觉非常不舒服
Now it's not just about me. lt feels extremely uncomfortable.
给我回电话
Call me back!
你好 丽斯贝丝
Hello Lisbeth.
你应该知道 我很抱歉让你陷入这种境地
You should know that I am sorry that you got into this situation.
我会尽一切可能帮助你
I'll try to help you in all possible ways.
我希望我们能合作 你和我
l hope that we can cooperate, you and me.
我觉得我们已经很熟了 你和我
l thought we got acquainted pretty well, you and me.
在那段时间里
During that time.
你是个固执的
You were a stubborn...
而且非常难治疗一个12岁的女孩
...and extremely difficult to treat twelve - year - old girl.
你咬过我的手指一次
You bit my finger once.
你还记得吗
Do you remember?
你永远不会明白触摸是治疗的一部分
You never understood that touch was part of the treatment...
它创造了亲密和信任
...and that it creates closeness and trust.
这尤其适用于儿童
This applies in particular to children.
你意识到我就是那个
Do you realize that I am the person...
谁最有潜力帮助你
...who has the greatest potential to help you?
你不觉得吗
Don't you?
嗨你还在吗 - 我给你的手机打了好几次电话
Hi. Are you still here? - I called your cellphone several times.
我正在写作 然后把它关掉了
I was writing and had it turned off.
同一个发送者
The same sender.
克里斯特今天试着报警了但我阻止了他
Christer tried to call the police today. But I stopped him.
我们必须马上解决这件事 迈克
We must fix this right now, Mikael.
你和我在经营这本杂志
You and I are running the magazine.
我们对员工负有责任现在不仅仅是你和我的问题了
We have responsibilities towards our employees. It is not just about you and me now.
我已经联系了利斯贝思的黑客伙伴之一 普雷格
l've contacted one of Lisbeth's hacker buddies, Plague.
这样我们就不用向警方报告了
So we don't have to report it to the police?
如果有人能找到发送者 那就是他 但这需要时间
If anyone can find the sender, then it's him, but it takes time.
它会比警察更快
It will be faster than the police.
我们说的是几天吗 或者几个星期
Are we talking about days? Or weeks?
坦率地说 我并不知道
Frankly, l do not know.
如果我们假设千禧年有什么要出版的
If we assume that Millennium has something to publish...
那他们还能有什么呢
...then what can they possibly have?
最糟糕的情况是 他们有一份比约克调查的副本
The worst - case scenario is that they have a copy of Björck's investigation.
但他们可能对我们的业务一无所知
But they may not know anything about our business.
尽管如此 他的可信度很高这本杂志也是如此
Nevertheless, he has high credibility. And the same goes for the magazine.
也许我们可以以某种方式降低可信度
Maybe we could reduce the credibility somehow?
总之
Anyway...
我们必须结束这一切 一劳永逸
...we have to put an end to this, once and for all.
她凌晨三点一刻给我们打了电话
She called us quarter past three in the morning.
她把自己锁在楼上的一个房间里
She had locked herself up in a room upstairs.
20分钟后我们到了那里 - 你找到什么踪迹了吗
We were there 20 minutes later. - Did you find any tracks?
警方已经处理了这件事我们现在已经在房子里安装了警报器
The police took care of that. We have installed alarms in the house now.
埃里卡告诉我那些电子邮件的事了
Erika told me about those e - mails.
他们可能与昨晚发生的事情有关
They are probably linked with what happened last night.
我的联系人正在努力追查他们 我不想把警察卷进来
My contact is trying to track them down. l do not want to involve the police.
你现在就应该这么做这是关于对你和埃里卡的身体威胁
You should do that now. lt's about physical threats towards you and Erika.
对我 - 对 甚至对你
Towards me? - Yes, even towards you.
你公寓里的无声闹钟昨晚响了
The silent alarm in your apartment went off last night.
我们在17分钟内就到了那里当我们搜查公寓时
We were there in 17 minutes. When we searched the apartment...
我们在你的一个扬声器里发现了180克可卡因
...we found 180 grams of cocaine hidden in one of your loudspeakers...
和12万瑞典克朗现金放在你的衣柜里
...and 120,000 Swedish crowns in cash in your wardrobe.
见鬼 - 他们想陷害你
What the hell?! - They're trying to set you up.
因为他们不能冲击杂志
Since they cannot hit the magazine.
它还在吗 - 只有钱
ls it still there? - Only the money.
可卡因已经被拿走了
The cocaine has been taken away.
我得给艾瑞卡打电话 - 我想她睡着了
I have to call Erika. - I think she's asleep.
埃里卡 - 是我
Erika. - lt's me.
我知道发生了什么糟透了
I know what has happened. lt sucks!
我想见你 我能来吗 - 不 别来
l want to see you. Can l come? - No, don't come here.
我们以后再谈这件事
We will talk about it later.
我现在想见你 - 我得睡几个小时
I want to see you now. - I have to sleep a few hours.
那么是在三点吗
At three o'clock then?
在Samir的Gryta餐厅
At Samir's Gryta?
你来不来 - 三点钟我会来的
Will you come or not? - At three o'clock. I will come.
好的再见 - 再见
Good. Bye. - Bye.
我会把这三页打印出来
l'll print those three pages.
你有埃里卡的消息吗
Have you heard anything from Erika?
我跟她谈过了她昨晚感觉不舒服 想在白天睡觉
I talked to her. She felt bad last night and wanted to sleep during the day.
她现在怎么样了 - 好多了见鬼 我得走了
How is she now? - Better. Damn, l've got to go.
她还有更多的电子邮件吗
Has she got more e - mail?
我们所有人在这一版上都做得很好
We've really done a great job with this edition, all of us.
我们待会喝杯啤酒好吗 - 不 我在萨米尔有个会议
Shall we have a beer later? - No, I have a meeting at Samir.
这些人中有多少是不确定的
There is uncertainty about how many of these people...
与该部门的活动有关
...are connected to the Section's activities.
毕竟 我们可能还不知道有更多这样的人
After all, there may be more of them we do not know of yet.
我们已经确定了关键人物 他们将在协调一致的行动中被逮捕
We have identified the key persons and they will be arrested in a coordinated action.
稍后会提供更多有关这方面的信息
More information about this later.
现在是三点差十分我们现在休息 一小时后再在这里见面
It is ten to three now. We'll break now and meet here again in an hour.
今天发生什么事了吗 - 克林顿一直在做透析
Has something happened today? - Clinton has been on dialysis.
其他人来来去去
The other ones were coming and going.
乔纳斯·桑德伯格可能是唯一一个喜欢社交的人
Jonas Sandberg is probably the only one who has been social.
10时30分 他在布赖德昂的一家披萨店遇到了两个人
At 10.30 he met with two persons at a pizzeria in Bredäng.
他见了谁 - 我不认识他们
Whom did he meet? - I do not know them.
他们看起来像东欧人 - 那是尼科利奇兄弟
They looked like Eastern European guys. - Those are the Nikolic brothers.
汤米和米罗·尼科利奇来自塞尔维亚 但他们一直住在哈丁奇
Tomi and Miro Nikolic. From Serbia, but they have been living in Huddinge.
非常不讨人喜欢的类型南北战争期间的神枪手
Very unpleasant types. Sharpshooters during the Civil War.
米罗因袭击被通缉 但当然他们大部分时间都住在塞尔维亚 所以
Miro is wanted for assault, but of course they live in Serbia most of the time, so...
米凯尔
Mikael...
你好 萨米尔
Hello, Samir.
对不起 我来晚了
Sorry l'm late.
你好吗 - 你觉得怎么样
How are you? - What do you think?
你昨晚为什么不打电话 - 你能做什么
Why didn't you call last night? - What could you have done?
我打电话给弥尔顿安全公司 因为我需要帮助
l called Milton Security because I needed help.
我们必须退后 米克
We have to back off, Micke.
萨米尔的《格里塔》论S请快点给我接电话
Samir's Gryta on Söder. Connect me quickly, please.
我叫停了杂志 我叫来了印刷处
l have stopped the magazine and l have called the printing office.
这也影响到马琳和克里斯特的安全
This also affects Malin's and Christer's safety.
你给印刷厂打电话了吗 - 我不想承担责任
Did you call the printing office? - I don't want to take the responsibility.
太危险了 - 该死的
lt's too dangerous. - Damn it...
迈克 有你的电话 - 不 现在不行
Micke, there's a call for you. - No, not now.
他们说这很重要
They say that it's very important.
打扰了
Excuse me.
趴下
Get down!
他们在射击 - 从公园抄近路
They are shooting! - Cut through the park.
搞什么鬼
What the hell!
趴下
Get down!
警察 警察 举起手来
Police! Police! Hands up!
现在
Now!
警察 举起手来
Police! Hands up!
你好吗
How are you?
你没事吧
Are you okay?
给你 擦干你自己 - 你好吗
Here, wipe yourself off. - How are you?
尽快把布隆维斯特和伯杰弄出去
Get Blomkvist and Berger out as fast as possible.
从厨房出来
Out through the kitchen!
两名警察在餐厅用餐
The two police officers were eating at the restaurant...
并认出了这对兄弟 其中一人因袭击而被通缉
...and recognized the brothers, one of whom is wanted for assault.
当他们试图逮捕他们时 枪声响起 但没有人受伤
Gunfire broke out when they attempted to arrest them, but no one was injured.
兄弟俩现在被指控谋杀未遂
The two brothers are now charged with attempted murder.
该死的
Damn it!
Goddamned!
我和克里斯特和马林谈过了
I talked to Christer and Malin.
他们现在不能留在办公室 - 不
They cannot stay at the office now. - No...
我们今天可能会被杀
We could have been killed today.
我们两个都是
Both of us.
没有一份工作值得为之而牺牲
No job is worth dying for.
不是的
No.
我们不知道他们是想杀了你 米凯尔 还是埃里卡
We do not know if they just wanted to kill you, Mikael, or Erika as well.
但他们的想法是警察会发现毒品和金钱
But the idea was that the police would find drugs and money...
并将其与南斯拉夫的毒品交易联系在一起
...and associate it with a Yugoslav drug deal.
那办公室里的其他人呢 - 我们要把办公室关几天
What about the others at the office? - We're closing the office for a couple of days.
我们还将推迟该杂志的出版
We will also postpone the publication of the magazine.
那么 我建议对你和艾瑞卡进行个人保护
Then l suggest personal protection for you and Erika.
不 我不想有人跟踪我
No, l don't want anyone following me.
我们将看看事情现在会如何发展 - 你和她联系过了吗
We'll see how things develop now. - Have you contacted with her?
接下来会发生什么
What's going to happen?
我将首先坚持丽斯贝丝·萨兰德的精神治疗
I will insist firstly on psychiatric care for Lisbeth Salander...
其次是长期监禁
...and secondly a long prison sentence.
难道这不应该是反过来的吗
Shouldn't that be the other way round?
是的 但在这种情况下
Yes, but in this case...
精神病学报告是如此明确
...the psychiatric report is so explicit...
我别无选择
...that l have no alternative.
非常感谢
Thank you very much.
利斯贝丝·萨兰德的审判在斯德哥尔摩地区法院开始
The trial of Lisbeth Salander starts here in Stockholm's District Court...
下午1点 大约一个小时后
...at 1 p.m., in about an hour.
如你所见 预计将持续三天 面对大量观众
lt is expected to last three days, before a large audience, as you can see.
在初步调查中 警方和检察官
During preliminary investigation the police and the prosecutor...
已经向媒体提供了信息 而辩方拒绝置评
...have given information to the media, while the defence has refused to comment...
天哪时间到了吗
My God. ls it time?
我昨晚一夜没合眼 - 一切都会好起来的
I did not sleep a wink last night. - Everything will be fine.
当然
Of course...!
一切都会好的
It will be OK.
真的 - 谢谢再见再见
Indeed! - Thank you. See you later. Bye - bye.
再多一点 再多一点
A little more, a little more.
我只能后悔
I can only regret...
利斯贝丝·萨兰德在七次听证会上一句话也没说
...that Lisbeth Salander didn't say a single word during the seven hearings.
然而 这一事实并没有削弱任何指控
However, that fact does not weaken any of the charges.
谢谢
Thank you.
然后我让辩方发言
Then I give the floor to the defence.
谢谢
Thank you.
从辩方来看 我们拒绝所有指控
From the defence side we reject all the charges.
我们将证明检察官的说法是不正确的
We will prove that the prosecutor's claims are incorrect...
而且我的当事人面临严重的违法行为
...and that my client has been exposed to serious legal violations.
我会要求宣判我的当事人无罪
l will demand that my client be declared innocent...
废除她的监护权 并立即释放她
...that her guardianship be abolished and that she be released immediately.
谢谢
Thank you.
检察官有什么要补充的吗
Does the prosecutor have anything to add?
出于几个原因 我建议这场审判闭门进行
For several reasons I propose that this trial be conducted behind closed doors.
此案关乎弱势群体的精神状况和福利
The case is about the mental condition and the welfare of a vulnerable person...
以及被归类为机密的材料
...and about material that is classified as confidential...
而且在某些地区可能会影响到国家安全
...and in some areas may impact on national security.
我们今晚再谈
We'll talk tonight.
看起来不错
That looks good.
我将从努力带来一些澄清开始
l will start with an effort to bring some clarity...
你去戈塞贝加的原因
...to your reasons for going to Gosseberga...
试图杀死你的父亲亚历山大·萨拉琴科
...to try to kill your father, Alexander Zalachenko.
我们应该把你的沉默理解为你不回答问题的声明吗
Should we interpret your silence as a statement that you will not answer questions?
我将乐于回答问题
l will happily answer questions.
那么也许你可以回答这个问题
Then maybe you can answer the question.
我没有听到任何问题
I have not heard any question.
我问你去戈塞贝加有没有杀你父亲的意图
l asked if you went to Gosseberga with the intention to kill your father.
不 你说过你想试着阐明
No, you said you wanted to try to shed light...
我为什么要去戈塞贝加试图杀死我的父亲
...on why I went to Gosseberga in an attempt to kill my father.
这是一个概括性的声明 你在其中预料到了我的回答
That was a general statement in which you anticipated my answer.
回答问题 - 没有
Answer the question. - No.
不什么 - 这就是问题的答案
"No" what? - That's the answer to the question.
你有没有用斧头砍你父亲的头
Did you strike your father's head with an axe?
是
Yes.
他受了重伤 我辩称这是谋杀未遂
He was seriously injured and l argue that this is attempted murder.
你的看法是什么
What is your view?
这是两项指控 我应该对哪一个有意见
Those were two allegations. On which one should l have an opinion?
如果用斧头砍你父亲的头是谋杀未遂
If striking your father in the head with an axe was attempted murder.
那不是谋杀未遂这是自卫
That was not attempted murder. lt was self - defence.
谢谢
Thank you.
如果你需要什么 请告诉我
Tell me if you need anything.
你能拿到香烟吗 - 算了吧
Can you get cigarettes? - Forget it.
谢谢
Thank you.
你好 - 嗨
Hello. - Hi.
被看守的感觉如何 - 还不错
How does it feel to be guarded? - Well, not bad.
只要他们待在外面
As long as they stay outside.
埃里卡
Erika...
我做不到
I couldn't do it.
你是个自我主义者
You are an egotist.
还是个白痴
And an idiot.
我这周将呆在家里下个星期
l will stay at home this week. And next week.
我想确定 我的决定是正确的
I want to be sure that l made the right decision.
好吧
Well...
关于我们还是关于千禧年
About us or about Millennium?
关于这两件事
About both...
我想
...I think.
我会保持联系的
I'll be in touch.
你自己多保重
Take care of yourself.
该死的
Damn it.
萨兰德 是时候了
Salander, it's time.
丽斯贝丝·萨兰德的所谓自传
Lisbeth Salander's so - called autobiography...
缺乏任何可信度
...lacks any credibility.
有许多针对不同人的指控
There are a number of allegations against different people...
每个人都比另一个人更荒谬
...each one more absurd than the other.
一切都是一种表达
Everything is an expression...
莉斯贝丝·萨兰德所患的偏执型精神分裂症
of the paranoid schizophrenia Lisbeth Salander is suffering from.
你能举个例子吗
Can you give an example?
最明显的是对强奸的刻画
The most obvious is the portrayal of rape...
其中 - 她声称
...of which - she alleges...
她的监护人 律师比约曼 会被判有罪
...her guardian, advocate Bjurman, would be guilty of.
整个故事 所有的细节
The whole story, with all the details...
是怪诞幻想的经典例子
...is a classic example of the grotesque fantasies...
孩子们倾向于展示的东西
...which children tend to exhibit.
但利斯贝丝·萨兰德不再是一个孩子了 她是一个成年女性
But Lisbeth Salander is not a child anymore, she is an adult woman.
还有待决定
lt still remains to be decided...
她现在的精神状态到底是怎样的
...on what exact mental level she is now.
然而 原则上你是对的
However, in principle you are right.
我明白
I understand.
1993年 利斯贝思·萨兰德在圣斯蒂芬医院被迫入院
ln 1993 Lisbeth Salander underwent forced admission at St. Stephen's hospital.
在她住在那里的那些年里 你要对她负责
During the years she lived there, you were responsible for her.
对吗 - 对
ls that correct? - Yes.
她在床上躺了几天
How many days did she lie tied up?
换句话说：被夹在床上
ln other words: clamped to the bed.
我不太记得了但不是很多
I cannot quite remember. But not very many.
大约有多少人
How many approximately?
有可能 三十次但我不明白这个问题的相关性
Possibly... thirty times. But I don't understand the relevance of this question.
利斯贝丝·萨兰德本人声称这是381天
Lisbeth Salander herself claims it was 381 days.
这纯粹是幻想这没有任何意义
That is pure fantasy. It doesn't make any sense.
所以你是说 她躺在床上不超过一年
So you're telling me, she did not lie tied up more than one year...
她在那里住了两年 - 当然不是
...of the two years she lived there? - Of course not.
辩方一再试图调取莉斯贝丝·萨兰德的档案
The defence has repeatedly tried to get Lisbeth Salander's files...
讲述了她在圣斯蒂芬医院被迫入学的几年 但没有成功
...covering the years of her forced admission at St. Stephen's, but without success.
你能解释一下为什么吗 - 因为这是保密的
Can you explain why? - Because it's classified as confidential.
这是这类研究的一般规则
That is a general rule for this kind of study.
作为律师 你应该知道这一点
You as a lawyer should know that.
在这里 我有一份利斯贝思·萨兰德的卷宗 关于两年的时间：
Here l have a copy of Lisbeth Salander's dossier, regarding two years:
1993年和1994年
1993 and 1994.
这里清楚地写着 莉斯贝丝·萨兰德被绑了381天
Here it's clearly stated that Lisbeth Salander was tied up for 381 days.
詹尼尼辩护律师 这与这场审判有什么相关性
Advocate Giannini, what is the relevance of that for this trial?
我想证明彼得·泰尔博里安在这个问题上没有说实话
I want to prove that Peter Teleborian is not telling the truth on this subject.
詹尼尼律师 1993年和1994年的记录不能在今天使用
Advocate Giannini, records from 1993 and 1994 cannot be used today...
质疑彼得·泰尔博里安的可信度
...to question Peter Teleborian's credibility.
我明白
I understand.
我觉得自己像个白痴
I felt like an idiot.
当检察官提交Teleborian的新报告时 我将一无所获
When the prosecutor submits Teleborian's new report, l will have gained nothing.
她会再次被送进精神病院 而我什么也做不了
She will end up in the mental hospital again and I can't do a damn thing.
欢迎来到你的私人小女孩们
Welcome to your private young girls.
你是谁
Who are you?
瘟疫
Plague.
这是什么
What is this?
彼得·泰尔博里安的私人电脑一份USB拷贝
Peter Teleborian's private PC. A USB copy.
对不起进来
I'm sorry. Come in.
里面装的是什么
What does it contain?
你需要的一切
Everything you need.
外加一些肮脏的垃圾
Plus some nasty shit.
安妮卡 我这里有你们需要的一切与部门的合作
Annika, l have everything you'll need right here. Cooperation with the Section...
几个版本的精神病报告 假的日期
...the psychiatric report in several versions, fake dates...
电子邮件通信 所有的一切
...e - mail correspondence, everything.
好了 你来了太棒了
Well, there you are. Excellent.
这里 - 我永远没有时间把这些都读完
Here. - I will never have time to read all this.
在午餐时读一读日期很重要
Read it during lunch. The dates are important.
很好 太棒了 再见再见
Good, great! See you later. Bye - bye.
你最后去了圣斯蒂芬大教堂
You ended up at St. Stephen's...
把汽油倒在你父亲身上 然后点燃它
...after pouring petrol onto your father and lighting it.
是 - 你为什么要这么做
Yes. - Why did you do that?
因为他虐待我母亲好几年了
Because he had abused my mother for several years.
1993年6月12日 他如此残忍地殴打她 导致她残疾
On June 12 1993, he assaulted her so brutally that she became disabled.
她有永久性的脑损伤 - 你告诉别人了吗
She had permanent brain damage. - Did you tell anyone?
是的 对审问我的警官
Yes, to the police officer who interrogated me...
给社会福利委员会 各种医生 一位牧师和那边的那头猪
...to the Social Welfare Board, various doctors, a priest and that pig over there.
当 我来到圣斯蒂芬教堂时 我试图解释所发生的事情
When l came to St. Stephen's, I tried to explain what had happened.
但他声称 这是 我的幻想作为惩罚 我被绑了起来
But he claimed that l fantasized. As punishment l was tied up.
那纯粹是胡说八道再说一次 这是一个事实的例子
That's pure nonsense. Again, an example of the fact...
你的委托人缺乏区分幻想和现实的能力
...that your client lacks the ability to separate fantasy from reality.
你撒谎 你这头该死的猪 - 利斯贝丝 我们在法庭上使用适当的语言
You lie, you fucking pig. - Lisbeth, in court we use proper language.
我现在想继续性侵
l would like to proceed now with the sexual abuse...
律师尼尔斯·比约曼将我的当事人暴露给了他
...to which advocate Nils Bjurman exposed my client.
这不是案件的一部分
That is not part of the case.
这些都是荒谬的指控 没有任何证据
Those are absurd allegations without any shred of evidence.
这是利斯贝思面临的滥用法律权力的一个例子
It is an example of the abuse of legal power to which Lisbeth has been exposed.
关于弗雷德里克·克林顿：他可能正在接受透析
With respect to Frederick Clinton: he might be on dialysis...
在这种情况下 在卡罗林斯卡医院
...in this case, at Karolinska Hospital.
这里的每个人都将收到所有必要的信息
Everyone here will receive all necessary information.
我重复一遍第1组：Bublanski组
I repeat. Group 1 : Bublanski.
第2组：Svensson组
Group 2: Svensson.
第3组：模型组
Group 3: Modig.
第4组：Figuerola组
Group 4: Figuerola.
第5组：Holmberg组
Group 5: Holmberg.
如有疑问或含糊之处 你可以联系你的部门主管
In case of questions or ambiguities you can contact your chief of division.
祝好运
Good luck.
你已经宣布尼尔斯·比约曼律师强奸了你 - 是的
You have declared that advocate Nils Bjurman has raped you? - Yes.
这应该是什么时候发生的 - 不是 应该
When did that supposedly happen? - Not "supposedly".
这件事发生在2008年2月18日星期二
It happened Tuesday, February 18, 2008...
和同年3月7日星期五这一点在我的传记中写得很清楚
...and Friday, March 7 of the same year. It is clearly written in my biography.
你向警方报案了吗 - 没有
Did you report the rape to the police? - No.
有何不可 - 警察从来没有听过我的话
Why not? - The police had never listened to me.
你有没有为你的伤势寻求医疗帮助
Did you search medical help for your injuries?
不是的
No.
你跟别人谈过了吗 - 没有
Did you talk to someone about it? - No.
已故的尼尔斯·比约曼从未被判有罪
The late Nils Bjurman has never been convicted of any crime.
他从未向警方举报过 也从未受到过任何调查
He has never been reported to the police nor has he been the subject of any investigation.
然而 我的任务是提醒你 萨兰德
However, it's my task to remind you that Salander...
被诊断为偏执型精神分裂症
...has been diagnosed as paranoid schizophrenic.
她在一家儿童精神科诊所待了几年
She has spent several years in a psychiatric clinic for children...
从她18岁生日起就一直受到监护
...and has been under guardianship since her eighteenth birthday.
无论这可能多么令人遗憾 它当然有其原因
However regrettable that may be, it has its reasons of course.
丽斯贝丝·萨兰德有她自己非常混乱的世界观
Lisbeth Salander has her very own confused world - view...
这一点在她的《自传》中表现得非常清楚
...which appears very clearly in her "autobiography".
在其他任何地方 她对现实的缺乏接触都没有得到如此明显的证明
Nowhere else has her lack of contact with reality been demonstrated so clearly.
在这种情况下
In this context...
我们将努力评估她的话和声明的可信度
...we will try to assess the credibility of her words and statements.
检察官说完了吗 - 说完了
Has the prosecutor finished? - Yes.
然后辩方可以提出她的证据 - 谢谢你
Then the defence may present her evidence. - Thank you.
彼得·泰尔博里安声称莉斯贝丝·萨兰德在撒谎
Peter Teleborian claims that Lisbeth Salander is lying...
关于她被律师比约曼性侵的指控
about her allegations that she was sexually abused by advocate Bjurman.
检察官也有同样的看法
The prosecutor is of the same opinion.
我现在将证明利斯贝思的断言是绝对正确的
I will now demonstrate that Lisbeth's assertion is absolutely true.
这段录音是什么时候录制的
When was this recording made?
2008年3月7日 我用的是隐藏式摄像头
On March 7, 2008. l used a hidden camera.
如果你对我好
If you are nice ...
如果你
lf you...
如果你对我好
If you are nice...
那么 我就会很友善
...Then l'll be nice.
你会表现得友善些吗
Are you going to be nice?
你人好吗 你对我好吗
Are you nice? Are you being nice?
现在已经太晚了
It is too late now.
别拍了
Stop the film!
足够了
That's enough!
你为什么要拍 - 尼尔斯·比约曼以前强奸过我
Why did you film it? - Nils Bjurman had raped me before.
他强迫我给他口交
He had forced me to give him oral sex.
如果 我想要我的钱 他会要求更多的性生活
He demanded more sex if l wanted my money.
这是获取不利于他的证据的唯一途径
It was the only way to obtain evidence against him.
唯一能让他停下来的方法
The only way to make him stop.
我们休息一下休息一小时
We'll take a break. A one hour break.
对不起 我来晚了 - 没关系的谢谢
Sorry I am late. - lt's okay. Thank you.
你要提交新的文件吗
Are you presenting new documents?
不 它们与最高法院已经拥有的相同 但有微小但关键的区别
No, they are the same as the court already has, however, with minor but crucial differences.
我稍后会讲到的
l will come to it later.
然后我让辩方发言 - 谢谢你
Then I give the floor to the defence. - Thank you.
好吧
Well...
没有人能再否认利斯贝思是受害者
No one can deny any longer that Lisbeth was the victim...
被她的监护人尼尔斯·比约曼律师严重性侵
...of serious sexual abuse by her guardian, advocate Nils Bjurman.
一个她认为她可以信任的人
A person she thought that she could trust.
正如我已经说过的 它说明了对利斯贝思的攻击类型
As I have said, it illustrates the type of assaults against Lisbeth.
这些攻击既是心理上的 也是司法上的
The attacks have been both psychological and judicial.
对此负有主要责任的人是彼得·泰尔博里安博士
The person who bears a major responsibility for this, is Dr. Peter Teleborian.
1993年 他写了一份精神病学报告
In 1993 he has written a psychiatric report...
和冈纳·比约克一起
...together with Gunnar Björck...
他是安全局内部一个非法组织的成员
... - who was a member of an illegal group inside the Security Service..
为了让一个危险的证人闭嘴
...in order to silence a dangerous witness...
就这样 莉斯贝丝·萨兰德被关进了一个安全的精神病室
...and thus Lisbeth Salander got locked up in a secure psychiatric unit.
这些指控一定是有限度的
There must be a limit to these allegations...
打扰一下 现在 我请你发言
Excuse me, but now l have the floor.
这发生在丽斯贝丝向她父亲浇了汽油之后
This happened after Lisbeth had poured petrol on her father...
亚历山大·萨拉琴科绝望地试图救她的母亲
...Alexander Zalachenko, in a desperate attempt to save her mother.
但那些保护萨拉琴科的人
But those who protected Zalachenko...
确保掩盖这件事 并对调查进行保密
...made sure to cover it up and classified the investigations.
在彼得·泰尔博里安的帮助下
And with Peter Teleborian's help...
他们把莉斯贝丝囚禁在乌普萨拉的圣斯蒂芬医院
...they imprisoned Lisbeth at St. Stephen's Hospital in Uppsala.
这是一项无耻的指控
That's an outrageous accusation!
我试着从各个方面帮助莉斯贝丝·萨兰德她试图
I have tried to help Lisbeth Salander in every way. She attempted...
昨天 彼得·泰尔博里安提交了他的新的法医精神病学报告
Yesterday Peter Teleborian presented his new forensic psychiatric report.
再一次 他提议
Once again, he proposes..
强制拘留和监禁利斯贝丝·萨兰德
...compulsory detention and imprisonment of Lisbeth Salander.
但就像1993年一样 这也是一件赝品
But just like in 1993 this is also a forgery.
这完全是
That is completely...
我必须请你允许辩方完成她的发言
l must ask you to allow the defence to finish her speech!
谢谢
Thank you.
他的观点是基于我当事人的 观察
His opinion is based on the "observation" of my client.
那一定是在她被转移到克罗诺贝格监狱后发生的
That must have happened after she was transferred to Kronoberg prison...
10月6日 11月5日完成
...on October 6, and completed on November 5.
对吗 彼得·泰尔博里安
ls that correct, Peter Teleborian?
我想传唤两名证人
l would like to call in two witnesses.
不是的
No!
警察 放下武器
Police! Drop your weapon!
好吧 你知道这份文件吗
Well... do you know this document?
是
Yes.
这是彼得·泰尔博里安写的关于丽斯贝丝·萨兰德的精神病学报告
lt is the psychiatric report on Lisbeth Salander by Peter Teleborian.
有三个版本
There are three versions.
第一张日期是9月20日 第二张是10月1日
The first dated September 20, the second October 1 ...
这是第三张 日期是10月6日
...and this one is the third, dated October 6.
你把文件给了我
You gave me the documents.
我注意到 10月1日的第一份报告
And I have noticed that the first report of October 1 ...
与彼得·泰尔博里安昨天提交的报告一模一样
...is identical to the report which Peter Teleborian presented yesterday.
日期为11月5日
Dated November 5.
说得委婉些 非常奇怪
Very odd, to put it mildly.
我的结论是彼得·泰尔博里安写了这些报告
My conclusion is that Peter Teleborian has written the reports...
在他观察利斯贝丝·萨兰德之前
...before he observed Lisbeth Salander.
出于这个原因 它缺乏所有的可信度
For this reason it lacks all credibility.
埃德克林警长 这是真的
Superintendent Edklinth, it is true...
你从Mikael Blomkvist那里收到了关于Salander的这些报告
...that you have received these reports about Salander from Mikael Blomkvist?
是
Yes.
你的总体结论是什么 - 它们是错误的
What are your overall conclusions? - They are false.
它们是很久以前写的
They were written long before...
彼得·泰尔博里安有机会在监狱里见到丽斯贝丝·萨兰德
...Peter Teleborian had the opportunity to meet Lisbeth Salander in prison.
此外 它们是在某个乔纳斯·桑德伯格的合作下完成的
Moreover, they were completed with the collaboration of a certain Jonas Sandberg.
那是瞎说
That's a lie.
这是谎言吗 - 不 一点也不
Is it a lie? - No, not at all.
文件上注明了日期 还有电子邮件通信
The documents are dated and there is e - mail correspondence...
彼得·特雷伯里安和乔纳斯·桑德伯格之间的竞争证明了这一点
...between Peter Teleborian and Jonas Sandberg that proves it.
他是安全局一个秘密组织的成员
He is part of a clandestine group within the Security Service...
自70年代末S以来一直保护亚历山大·萨拉琴科的人
...who have protected Alexander Zalachenko since the late 70's.
该组织对这一决定负有责任
The group was responsible for the decision...
1993年将利斯贝思·萨兰德关在圣斯蒂芬医院
...to lock up Lisbeth Salander at St. Stephen's hospital in 1993.
乔纳斯·桑德伯格是十几个人中的一个
Jonas Sandberg is one of a dozen people...
根据总检察长的命令于今天逮捕了他们
...who were arrested today by order of the General Prosecutor.
桑德伯格涉嫌参与谋杀贡纳·比约克
Sandberg is suspected of involvement in the murder of Gunnar Björck...
可能还有另一起谋杀案我们有证据和几份法定声明
...and probably another murder. We have evidence and several statutory declarations.
彼得·泰尔博里安会对此发表评论吗
Would Peter Teleborian like to comment on this?
两名警察正在法庭外等候
Two policemen are waiting outside the courtroom.
他们想把彼得·泰尔博里安带走审问
They want to take away Peter Teleborian for interrogation.
为什么
Why?
他将因涉嫌严重违反儿童色情制品法而被逮捕
He will be arrested on suspicion of serious violation of the law on child pornography...
具体地说 拥有8000张儿童色情图片和电影
Specifically, for possession of 8,000 child pornography images and movies...
在他的电脑上找到的
...found on his computer.
这台电脑被没收了
This computer is confiscated.
请跟我们来
Please follow us.
请坐
Please sit.
法院还没有能够评估所有的信息
The court has not been able to assess all the information yet...
但找不到理由拘留莉斯贝丝·萨兰德
...but finds no reason to keep Lisbeth Salander in custody.
因此 你在等待判决期间是自由的
Therefore, you are free pending the verdict.
你确定你不想和我一起去千禧年吗
Are you sure that you don't want to go with me to Millennium?
你可以让我在Folkungagatan这里下车
You can drop me here on Folkungagatan.
你知道这是你欠米克的 对吧
You know that you owe this to Micke, right?
是但是
Yes. But...
是
Yes.
我一定能找到你 - 你可以用电子邮件联系我
l must be able to get hold of you. - You can reach me by e - mail.
好吧
Okay.
再见
See you.
进展如何 - 正义占上风
How did it go? - Justice prevailed.
现在有派对了 - 现在有派对了
So now there is a party? - Now there is a party.
你现在要做什么 - 现在开始
What will you do now? - Now it starts!
涉嫌谋杀 以及其他事情
...suspected of murder, among other things.
在斯德哥尔摩这间公寓里开展活动的组织
The organization that carried out its activities from this apartment in Stockholm...
对莉斯贝丝·萨兰德的严重法律攻击负有责任
...was responsible for serious legal assaults against Lisbeth Salander.
然而 这个故事始于60年代的S
However, the story started in the 60's.
该部门当时成立的目的是为了维护国家利益
The Section was founded then to watch over the nation's interests.
根据官方说法 他们从未存在过 也从未在这间公寓里操作过
Officially they never existed and operated from this apartment.
有证据表明 即使是国家警察局长也不知道该组织
Evidence suggests that even the head of the National Police was not aware of the group.
70年代中期 S部门招募了一名苏联顶级间谍
In the mid - 70's the Section recruited a top Soviet spy...
利斯贝思已被释放 等待判决
Lisbeth has been released pending the verdict.
因此 她要么被无罪释放 要么被判处缓刑
So, she will either be acquitted or receive a suspended sentence.
给你 - 这是什么 房地产库存
Here you are! - What is this, "Estate inventory"?
这是萨拉琴科留下的遗产
It's the legacy of Zalachenko.
我不想要那头猪的任何东西
I don't want anything from that pig.
没有 但你现在是法定年龄了
No, but you are of legal age now.
因此 我需要你的签名来证明你收到了它
Therefore, I need your signature to prove that you received it.
价值300,000美元的证券
Securities with a value of 300,000...
外加戈塞贝加价值150万英镑的房产
...plus property in Gosseberga valued at 1 ,5 million.
我不想和这件事有任何瓜葛
I don't want to have anything to do with it.
然后就是这个
Then there is this...
在Norrtälje郊外的某个废弃砖场
An abandoned brickyard somewhere outside Norrtälje.
只有这块地的估价为15万英镑
Only the plot has been valued at 150,000.
好吧
Okay.
卖掉所有的狗屎 然后把钱送人
Sell all the shit and give the money away.
我认为你应该读一读
l think you should read it.
我以后可以帮你卖
l can sell it for you later.
米克向你问好
Micke says hello to you.
比萨·布索拉 给你 - 谢谢再见
Pizza Bussola? Here you are! - Thank you. Bye.
这是什么狗屎
What is this shit?
你应该去死 你这个该死的怪胎
You deserve to die, you fucking freak.
电话信息服务 - 是的 你好
Telephone information service. - Yes, hello.
请告诉我Svavelsjö摩托车俱乐部的电话号码
Please give me the number of the Svavelsjö motorcycle club.
是谁 - 你对尼德曼感兴趣吗
Who is there? - Are you interested in Niedermann?
我听着呢
I'm listening.
紧急情况
Emergency.
警察杀手Ronald Niedermann在Norrtälje的Skederyd砖厂
Cop killer Ronald Niedermann is at Skederyd's brickyard in Norrtälje.
一个摩托团伙要杀了他他们全副武装
A motorcycle gang is going to kill him. They are heavily armed.
我打扰您了吗
Am l interrupting you?
我正在洗澡 - 哦 我明白了
l was having a bath. - Oh, I see...
你看新闻了吗 - 没有
Have you seen the news? - No.
罗纳德·尼德曼去世了一个来自Svavelsjö的帮派杀了他
Ronald Niedermann is dead. A gang from Svavelsjö has killed him.
然后警察来了 把所有人都逮捕了
Then the police came and arrested the whole lot.
谢谢你所做的一切
Thanks for everything.
不必介意
Don't mention it.
谢谢你自己
Thanks yourself.
再见
See you.
再见 - 当然
See you. - Definitely.